Hey everyone, welcome to WP Manage
Ninja. If you're running a nonprofit
organization or you're thinking of
starting one, you already know how hard
it is to juggle the volunteers, events,
and the campaigns that come along with
it. Basically, it's like spreadsheets
everywhere, email threads that never
end, and confused about who's doing
what. Sounds familiar. Yep, I know. So
today, I'll show you how to ditch that
chaos and run everything smoothly inside
your WordPress site using our very
amazing plug-in, Fluent Boards. We'll
walk through how to manage different
kinds of campaigns and how to set it up
and how everything works in Fluent
Boards. So, I'll basically build a dummy
nonprofit setup so you can see it in
action. Grab your coffee, hit that like
button, and let's simplify your mission.
So to start with everything, you first
have to install the Fluent Boards
plugin. As you can see on my screen, I
already have it installed and I am
currently on the dashboard. I don't have
any boards or any tasks on my board yet
because I've just installed it. And
everything looks very neat and very
intuitive, very straightforward for if
you're using a plug-in in a very
beginner phase. So, as you can see, I
don't have anything on my dashboard, but
we will have something by the end of
this video. You can see that they have
boards. This option for boards basically
all the boards that you have or you will
have will show up over here. So,
different boards and different projects
will accumulate over here. Over here is
the reports section. Here you'll see all
the reports and information gathering
over here. This is the settings option
where you'll be able to go through
different kinds of settings that we will
see later on. So let's get started with
making the project board. At first you
have to go over there and create a
board. So we are going to go and give it
a
title and a
description for the board. All right. So
as you can see I have two options over
here. one is the project management and
one is public road map. So this option
comes up when we turn on the fluent road
map extension. So what is fluent road
map? It's basically an add-on that comes
completely free with fluent boards pro.
It's a handy tool to get suggestions,
feature requests or any other relevant
information from clients, leads or
anyone interested in your business. So I
can create one just like I created my
project board and embed it into my
website easily to interact with
potential clients directly. So this
extension can be pretty handy if you're
in that situation. But for today I'm
just going to go with the project
management option and save it. So the
board has appeared. As you can see I
have a very clean and intuitive board. I
can see that I have three stages already
and no tasks added. So now I'm going to
show you everything inside a board and
how you can add tasks and how to manage
everything within the tasks. So these
over here are the stages for my tasks.
So I can easily go ahead and drag and
drop these stages wherever I
like. Okay. So these stages have this
option of adding task. So basically you
can add tasks in each of the stages that
you can assign to assignees later on. So
this is my stage the first one. I can
easily go ahead and rename that stage to
whatever I want. Okay. So I'm naming my
first stage as organizers tasks where
I'll save all the tasks for the
organizers. So I'm going to go ahead and
add
task and give it a
title. All right. Right. So, I'm going
to go ahead and save it. So, as you can
see, I have my first task on my first
stage. So, this task basically, you can
go ahead and uh change the settings and
add some new things within the task. So,
let's see how to do that. To do that,
we're going to go and click on the task.
So this is a task page where you can set
everything within the task starting from
assignees the assignees that you want to
add for this task the dates that you
want this task to be fulfilled by as you
can see that there's a due date option a
start date option you can set it up to
your preference I'm going to go ahead
and save it okay so this is a very
interesting button over here which is
the priority button so what this button
does is if your task is super important
or in an urgent time, you can go ahead
and set the high priority option. If
it's not that urgent or not that
important, you can go for the medium
option. And if you want to go slow with
that task, you can easily go ahead and
set it to the low priority option. So,
this is very very handy if you want to
have an overview of each of the task and
which task you want to finish by the end
of due dates. it. I feel like it's a
very important and very handy feature.
So, next is the labels option. This
option works like a marker by which you
can mark your task or color code your
task. So, if you have a number of tasks
in your hand, you can just color code it
and add it to your preference. All
right, moving on to the description tab.
So this section as you can see it has a
very rich text field over where you can
add the description or the important
information for the task. So whatever
you write in the description, you can
add hyperlinks. You can even add media
in the description. Okay, to show you
guys an example, I'm just going to go
ahead and paste a dummy text. All right,
so as you can see, I have a dummy text
over here. I can easily bold the text. I
can make this and customize it the way I
want it to. So, it's a very handy and
important feature that you can use. So,
I'm going to go ahead and save it and
keep it as it is. So, now we have
arrived at the attachment section. So,
with this section, if you need any kinds
of images or any kinds of file that you
need to upload, you can go ahead and
choose this option and drag and drop
files. If your task requires that you
can go ahead and also paste links that
you need URLs that are required for the
task and you can also add a display text
for that specific
attachment. All
right. So the next section is a subtask
section. What this section does is if
your task becomes very huge or if you
feel like your task is very big, you can
go ahead and divide this task into
subtasks. You can add subtasks within
this task to make that task sectionated.
So let's go ahead and add some subtasks
for our nonprofit organization board. So
as you can see, I have added three
subtasks for my task. So you can go
ahead and set dates for that specific
subtask. As you can see, if I set it to
22 with starting date of 21, I can save
it just like that. I can even add
specified assignees for this specific
subtask. All right. And now you can go
ahead and edit it or delete the subtask
if you want and even convert that
specific subtask into a task. This is
amazing. So, I'm going to go ahead and
set this one up as well.
So as you can see I have set all of my
subtasks perfectly. So this is all about
subtask. All right. Below there is a
comment section where all of your
activities every single move that you
make will be recorded over here in this
section. So this is all about the
settings within the task. So, as we are
making a nonprofit organization board,
I'm going to go ahead and add a few more
tasks for you to understand it better.
So, as you can see, I have added a few
tasks and subtasks for you to understand
how a nonprofit organization can use
Fluent Boards. So, as I've created a
nonprofit organization, a dummy one. So,
I've added some tasks and subtasks along
with some stages. So you can and move
the stages according to your priority
needs just like that. It's very easy
drag and
drop. This is the canban view of the
board. What you can do is you can also
go for the list
view. If we go for the list view, you
can see everything comes up as a list
and then you can also view it in a
calendar view. So in the calendar view
your tasks view to you or come to you
according to the date your tasks or your
subtasks have been assigned. So this is
a very interesting view but let's go and
switch to canban view as I feel like
it's more convenient for me personally.
All right. So, you can also go ahead and
filter out according to the people
you've tasks according to assignees
apparently and then you can also select
stages and just view that specific
stage. As you can see, I've just put on
the organizers task and only the
organizer task is showing to me. If I go
and add
another stage, only that stage also
appears after that.
All right. So the next one is a task
status option. So in this one, okay, so
this section over here is a task status
option. So if you want to see only the
closed ones, you can go ahead and take
this one and only the closed ones are
going to appear here. So as I don't have
any of my tasks closed, none of it is
appearing over here. So let's go ahead
and undo that. And all my tasks appear
cuz none of them were closed earlier.
All right. So you can also view your
tasks and filter them out according to
dates or no dates or overdue. This is a
very handy option. You can also go for
tasks due this week or next month or all
the upcoming tasks all together. So if I
go for the overdue ones, I don't have
any cuz I don't have any of the tasks
overdue. Or if I go for tasks due in
today, the ones that are only due in
today will show up. So this filter
option is very very important if you
want to have a quick overview on what
task you have due today, tomorrow or
next week, whenever you want to see. You
can also filter them out through the
priority option. If you want to see only
the high priority task, you can take
this one and the high priority tasks are
going to appear over here. If you want
to see them with the medium ones, you
can also go ahead and choose this
option. And the low
ones, if you want, you can also filter
them out according to the labels. If I
go ahead and press this one, only the
yellow label ones show up. If I go ahead
and press the red one, the red label
ones show up. So, this filter option is
very, very handy. I'm going to go ahead
and clear this one to have an ultimate
view of all of my tasks. Also I forgot
to mention a very important detail in
fluent boards which is you can
apparently move tasks within the stage.
So if you want to suppose as this one is
high priority and I want to get it to
the top I can just drag it to the top.
How seamless is that? Not only that you
can also move the tasks to different
stages according to your preference. So
if I want to take this task, collect
forms task to the volunteers task stage,
I can simply just drag and drop it over
here. How cool is that? Okay, so let's
take it back to where it was. All right,
so this is all about the settings of the
stage and the tasks. Now let's see the
settings of the board. So for that,
let's go ahead over there. And you can
see all the settings for this board has
appeared. So if you click on this option
you can see a overview of this board. If
you can remember we put a description
before starting this board. This appears
over here. The info who this was created
by and when it was created on everything
comes up right here. You can also see
the board activity on what every single
move or how every single move was made.
Starting from the smallest detail to the
largest ones, all of them show up in the
board
activity. All right. So now the next one
is customizing your board. You can
basically change the background of the
board according to your preference. So
you have gradient option, solid option.
You can customize it according to your
preference. You can also add images as
the backgrounds. For today, let's just
go for gradients cuz they look pretty
nice. Okay. You can also, by the way,
customize the color according to your
preference.
Okay. All right. Let's go for this
one and close
this. All right. So, the next is the
notification settings. So this is a very
interesting settings because you can
turn on and turn off notifications for
the stages or for the moves that you
make. So if you want your assignees to
get notified about comments, you can
enable this. Or if you change any stage
or assign a task to anyone or if any
date has been updated or any task has
been archived, you can just simply
enable this option so that the assenees
or the members of this board get
notified for each and every move. And if
you don't want them to have any of the
notifications, you can just turn it off
and save it. So this ensures that board
members don't get notified. Okay. Moving
on to board labels. So usually people
can use this for uh naming or color
coding each of the departments. Suppose
if I take this option for green and I
name it polo for
suppose the polo ones are going to be
green. So this is a very handy feature.
Let's move on to the next one which is
the board members. Okay, this is a very
important section because in this one
you can add
members
for your board. So I'm going to go ahead
and show you by adding a few of my
members. All right. So as you can see I
have added three more members to my
board. So I have the option of
customizing their access to this board.
I can promote them to manager or I can
just keep them as viewers or I can go
ahead and remove them from board if
required. So I also have a universal
option over here to grant access with
view only permissions. So if I add
members over here, I can just simply tap
this and now whoever I'm going to add is
going to get access for viewing the
board only. So if I put the access for
viewing for the three people that I
added, they can only see the board. they
won't be able to make any kind of edits
or they won't be able to um add any task
or subtasks or whatever that the manager
can do. So I'm going to go ahead and
promote them to manager and leave this
page. Okay. So this is how you basically
add the board members. Now it's for the
archived item section. So over here if
you have any of the tasks archived or if
any of the stages archived you can
easily come here and check it out. So
let's see if we go ahead and archive
this stage for
suppose we can go ahead and see it in
the archived stages option. So if I
restore it it's easily going to come
back. It's the same for the tasks. If I
go ahead and archive this specific
task, I can easily go ahead and check it
out in the archive tasks option. This is
a very cool feature. Okay. So, I'm going
to go ahead and restore it. And it's
back over here. All right. So, the next
option is duplicating the board. If you
want to create a similar board for
suppose a different organization or
different event, you can go ahead and
easily duplicate this specific board and
you're going to have the same tasks and
the same labels just like this specific
board. You can also keep the
templates as it is and duplicate it. All
right. So this is the export option. You
can go ahead and export this entire
board to check it out later. And
finally, you have the option to archive
this board. So when you archive this
board, it shows as archived and you are
the only one that can see this board and
no one else. So this is basically all
the options for the main board settings.
So I forgot to mention about the task
settings. Although we already had a
huge discussion within the
tasks. You can quickly edit from outside
the task. As you can see, you can open
the task. You can copy this specific
tasks link. You can even add labels to
this task. And you can add subtasks from
top of here. You can even add
priorities. Everything that's inside the
main taskbar. and easily you can change
the cover and archive the task according
to your
need. All right. So I am done with
making my board. I have added my board
members. I have added the tasks and
subtasks. You can add as many stages as
you want. It's totally on you and we're
done making the board. So let's go ahead
and check out the report section. As we
didn't have any earlier made board or
tasks, we didn't see anything on the
report section. but I'm pretty sure we
will now. So, let's go ahead and check
it out. Okay, as you can see, I have a
total of 24 tasks. I also have a task
priority chart in which I can see how
many tasks are high, medium, and low. I
can see it in a pie chart view. I also
have a task completion chart on how many
tasks I have completed or how many tasks
I have overdue. I apparently have it in
all the views that I need. So this is
pretty cool. All right. So let's move to
the settings option. Via the settings
option, you can also change the roles of
the members that you have added on your
board. So earlier you saw that I added
the three users in my nonprofit
organization board. From here also I can
change their access to whatever I want,
viewer or member. and I can update the
X's. How easy is that? So, this was
apparently all about the nonprofit
organization board that we made today.
All right. So, the last but not the
least section is a front-end portal. So
this is a very important section because
if you don't want to give anyone access
to your WordPress site or dashboard, the
volunteers or the organizers or the
people that you add on your board can
easily access your board via the
front-end portal. Everything's going to
be the same. And yeah, that's basically
it. So, if you're ready to ditch the
chaotic situation and actually enjoy
managing your nonprofit organization,
try Fluent Boards today. And hey, if you
found this tutorial helpful, don't
forget to hit subscribe. I've got more
tutorials coming on the way. Just keep
your eye on WP Manage Ninja. Let me know
in the comments how you plan to use
Glint Boards, cuz I read every single
one of them.